Welcome to week two, day five.
둘째 주, 5일째예요
The last day of week two where a lot is coming together.
2주 차 마지막 날입니다 많은 일이 벌어지고 있죠
I am so grateful that you're sticking with it, and I'm going to make it worth your while because today
계속 함께해 줘서 정말 고마워요 보람을 느끼게 해 줄게요 오늘은
is going to be really, really good fun.
정말 재미있을 거예요
I'm excited to get into this.
Get it가 기대되네요
It's the big conclusion of the second week.
둘째 주의 대망의 결말이죠
Again, I'm going to keep saying what you can do.
전 계속 여러분이 뭘 할 수 있는지 말할 거예요
I think it's so important to celebrate your upskilling, you know, Transformers back to front.
트랜스포머의 성공을 축하하는 건 정말 중요해요
You can code against the frontier APIs, you can build an AI assistant, and you can add tools to give
프론티어 API에 대항해 코드를 작성할 수 있고 인공지능 보조를 만들 수 있고 전문 지식을 줄 도구를
it expertise.
추가할 수 있죠
Today we introduce agents.
오늘은 에이전트를 소개하죠
We talk about how agents can carry out more advanced sequential activities.
요원이 보다 진보된 순차적 작업을 수행하는 방법을 얘기했죠
And then we do something super fun creating a multimodal AI assistant using agents and tools.
그리고 아주 재미있는 걸 할 거예요 에이전트와 도구를 이용해 다중 모듈 인공지능 보조를 만드는 거죠
So what are agents?
에이전트가 뭐죠?
Agents, I should say.
요원이라고 해야겠죠
An agent I.
에이전트 I요
An agent.
에이전트요
It is one of these umbrella terms that people can use in different contexts.
다양한 상황에서 사용할 수 있는 우산형 용어 중 하나죠
So it is one of these things that, that that can mean different things to different people.
사람마다 다른 의미를 가질 수 있는 거예요
But generally speaking, most often people are talking about software entities that are autonomous.
하지만 일반적으로 사람들은 자율적인 소프트웨어 엔터티라고 하죠
They can perform tasks not just in the sense of taking an input prompt and generating text.
입력 프롬프트와 텍스트 생성에서만이 아니라 다른 작업도 수행할 수 있죠
Um, typical characteristics.
전형적인 특징이죠
Let's say they are autonomous.
자율적이라 치죠
They have some sort of agency, they are goal oriented, that they have some kind of thing that they're
일종의 기관이 있고 목표 지향적이며 어떤 일을 하려고
setting out to do, and that they are task specific.
설정하고 작업에 구체적이죠
They are usually specialized on being good at one thing or another.
보통 한 가지에 특화된 사람들이에요
Um, and they're typically designed to be part of something called an agent framework, which is a sort
에이전트 프레임워크라는 것의 일부로 설계되었는데 인간의
of environment in which agents can interact to solve more complex problems and potentially with limited
제한적인 개입으로 더 복잡한 문제를 해결하기 위해 에이전트가 상호 작용하는
human involvement.
환경이죠
So it's not like it's just a sort of request response situation with a human.
인간에게 요청하는 요청 대응 상황이 아니에요
But you can imagine this sort of environment where multiple software agents that could be combinations
하지만 이런 환경을 상상해 보세요 작업을 수행하기 위해 기존 소프트웨어와 상호
of llms along with traditional software interacting in order to carry out tasks.
작용하기 위해 다중 소프트웨어 에이전트가 llms의 조합이 될 수 있는 환경이요
And so some of the features you might expect is the ability to have memory or persistence that sort
여러분이 기대할 수 있는 기능은 메모리와 지속성인데 요청 응답을
of goes beyond just a request response, the ability to have some sort of decision making and orchestration
넘어서 의사 결정과 오케스트레이션을 할 수 있고 무엇을 계획할
about what does what are planning abilities.
수 있는지에 관한 거죠
And sometimes that is just a matter of the environment as some planning coded into it.
때로는 환경의 문제일 뿐입니다 그에 대한 어떤 계획으로 코드되어 있는 거죠
Sometimes you have an LLM which is responsible for planning.
계획을 책임지는 LLM이 있을 때도 있어요
It's a model that knows how to take complex problems and break it down into smaller problems for other
복잡한 문제를 작은 문제로 쪼개서 다른 모델이 해결하도록
models to take care of.
하는 모델이죠
And then use of tools is often also an example of a genetic AI.
도구를 사용하는 건 유전적 인공지능의 예죠
This is where, of course, as you are now very familiar, we give models the ability to do things like
이제 익숙해지셨겠지만 모델에 데이터베이스나 인터넷 연결 등
connect to databases or connect to the internet or whatever we want because we are providing it access
원하는 모든 것에 연결할 수 있는 기능을 제공합니다 기능에 액세스를 제공하고
to functions and we know how that works behind under the hood.
어떻게 작동하는지도 아니까요
Now we know that it's really just a fancy if statement, but it gives the effect that the Llms are able
그냥 if문인 걸 알지만 이건 Lms가 이걸 할 수 있다는 효과를
to do this.
주죠
So we're about to do a few things.
몇 가지 할 게 있어요
Let me just quickly sort of set the scene for you.
상황을 간단히 설명해 드리죠
We're going to first build a function that can generate images, a good multimodal use case.
먼저 이미지를 생성할 수 있는 함수를 만들겠습니다 좋은 다중 모듈 사용 사례죠
We're going to have an LLM call that can do that.
그걸 할 수 있는 LLM 호출을 할 거예요
And it's going to be a function that does it.
그걸 하는 함수가 되겠죠
And you can think of that in its own right as being like an agent.
그 자체로 에이전트라고 볼 수 있어요
It's like a piece of software that is able to take this very specific, specialized instruction and
아주 구체적이고 전문적인 지시를 그대로 실행하는 소프트웨어 같아요
That will be an artist that we will create in code with the help of Dall-E three, the the image generation
코드로 아티스트 작업을 할 거예요 오픈AI의 이미지 생성 모델인 달리
model from uh, OpenAI.
3의 도움을 받아서요
Uh, and, you know, if you want to to quibble, you could argue that image generation is not in itself
굳이 트집을 잡자면 이미지 생성은 LM과 무관하다고 주장할
an LM thing.
수도 있어요
Uh, lm being language models, but these days, generally llms are used interchangeably with the broader
lm은 언어 모델이지만 요즘엔 일반적으로 더 넓은 세대 인공지능 컨텍스트와
gen AI context.
교환적으로 사용되죠
And so one does tend to think of image generation and other kinds of multimodal generation as falling
이미지 생성이나 다른 다중 모듈 생성 역시 LM 엔지니어의 도구 키트에
within the LM engineer's, uh, toolkit.
포함된다고 생각하는 경향이 있죠
So we're then going to look to, to make agents these sort of, uh, these, these functions that are
에이전트를 만드는 걸 살펴볼 겁니다 이런 작업을 할 수 있는 이런
able to do things.
함수요
And we're going to add sound as well as images, and then we're going to have an agent framework in
이미지뿐 아니라 소리도 추가할 거예요 에이전트 프레임워크를 만들어
that we are going to teach our AI assistant, the same airline assistant that we've been working on
인공지능 보조를 가르칠 거예요 우리가 말하고 그리는 법을 연구했던
how to speak and draw.
항공사 보조요
All right, without further ado, I hope that sounds fun to you.
그럼 바로 시작하죠 재미있을 것 같아요?
I hope it sounds exciting because it's going to be it's going to be great.
흥미진진하게 들리면 좋겠네요 정말 멋질 테니까요
Uh, I can't wait to do it.
빨리 하고 싶어요
Let's go and do it right now.
지금 당장 가죠